[Music]
foreign
ladies and gentlemen welcome back to
another fantastic homeless romantic
podcast some today we have somebody very
special who put his life on the line to
tell the American public what they
needed to know about the torture program
xcia whistleblower Mr John kiriaku how
are you John hey doing well thanks
thanks for having me uh I wanted to
start off by saying John has a radio
show uh that has been banned on most
every platform he's currently he's been
de-platformed and everybody knows right
now that the mainstream media and the
the government is going in overdrive
trying to silence anybody who's not for
the Ukraine war or for this and that the
other so it's really important John's
radio show it's on Sputnik if you can
find it just search around but
he's going to talk about the topics that
nobody else is going to talk about
um
so welcome to the show John thank you I
appreciate it I want to blast through a
few questions that I had prepared
um in response to I tell people shortly
yeah you you were CI whistleblower
um
you told people about the you you talked
to the journalists about there being a
torture program it was fine for a few
years the Obama Administration as things
change Obama came in and actually was
more cruel to whistleblowers than he'd
ever been than any other president yeah
and essentially
um
reopen the case threw you under the bus
and made you serve
how much was it 22 months 23 months 23
months yep and uh
and basically uh started a new era of
cracking down on whistleblowers that um
is still going on today and we're still
it's still getting harder and harder to
do things like this
um yes and then later there's some
issues with uh you interacting with
Trump and and trying to get apart from
him and of course not to no avail I'm
assuming
um and to this day are you still a felon
technically or do you have a passport is
it oh yeah no I yeah I've paid my debt
to society so uh I've got a passport I I
travel extensively
um I just got back from uh from Israel
on Tuesday and earlier in the month I
was in London and I was in Saudi Arabia
in July so I travel a lot but um
what a what a pardon would do for me is
it would give me back my uh my pension
my federal pension which was confiscated
so uh you know I had 770 000 saved in
that pension I'd like to have it back
yeah that's really why I'm going for the
pardon but yeah otherwise you know as
soon as I got out of prison I applied
um for a state pardon through the office
of the governor of Virginia it was Terry
McAuliffe at the time
and man that guy's office could not have
been any more helpful any more kind that
they expedited it I got this big
certificate with a gold seal and the
governor's signature on it they
reinstated all my civil rights so for me
it's all about the pension okay okay
yeah and for everybody out there
listening this is a man who risked his
life to tell you guys all that there was
malfeasance and uh maybe you could write
your Congressman write your I don't know
how politics work anymore but just I
appreciate that thank you try to try to
uh Shine the spotlight on this man for
what he's done thank you for that so
I'll start with my line of questions so
I I really the CIA is a sketchy
organization and it's famous for doing
very sketchy things in the dark and
stuff so how did you begin your career
and how what was your rep like what did
you think of them at the time what was
known about the CIA right and uh has it
has your opinion about that changed over
time well dramatically to answer the
easy question uh dramatically
uh I I didn't apply to the CIA the CIA
came to me uh I was in grad school at
George Washington University and I was
taking a class called the psychology of
leadership fascinating class being
taught by an eminent psychiatrist by the
name of Gerald post he had a he had a
PhD in political science a PhD in
Psychology and an MD and he called
himself a political psychiatrist
so um he assigned us a paper one day
where we had to Shadow our bosses for a
week and write a psychological profile
of our bosses
so um
I uh I was working at the United Food
and Commercial Workers International
Union at the time at their headquarters
here in Washington and
I I worked for this guy who was sort of
an old school tough
mean
you know son of a gun he had his back
broken by scabs during a strike and it
was he was just one of these old-time
tough guys
you know you see pictures of uh
of these old school Union guys with
baseball bats and stuff that was him
so halfway through the week
I'm actually a little bit afraid of him
and halfway through the week we had an
argument and I called him a racist which
he was
and he got so angry he balled up his
fists and I put up my hands because I
thought oh I went too far this time I
put up my hands and he says
my penis is bigger than yours
and I said what
and he says my penis is bigger than
yours
and I said you know what you're nuts and
I quit and I walked out I quit
so I wrote my paper I said that he was a
sociopath with Psychopathic and possibly
violent tendencies
backed it up you know with evidence and
stuff
and turned in the paper a week later I
get it back from Dr post and he gave me
an A and he wrote in the margin please
see me after class so
I went to see him and I said Dr post you
wanted to see me yeah close the door he
says I closed the door
and he says listen I'm not really a
professor here I'm a CIA officer
undercover as a professor here and I'm
looking for people who might fit into
the cia's culture I think you would fit
in would you like to join the CIA
well the truth was I was getting married
like six weeks later I had no job I had
a masters of just finishing a master's
degree in legislative affairs which
wasn't going to do anything for me
and so I said sure why not always wanted
to see the the world interested in
public service and uh the next thing I
knew I was I was in the CIA had you ever
seen a James Bond movie up until that
point oh yeah yeah no I loved it I I
loved the idea of it I loved the the
subterfuge and you know the excitement
and I I had done a lot of traveling in
college I had gone to two dozen
countries in college just on my own you
know with a backpack and my girlfriend
and stuff but
but this this sounded exciting and like
I say you know I come from an immigrant
family and and public service was always
something that was very very important
in our household you know we were very
grateful for the opportunities that this
country gave us and so I actually only
looked at jobs in in public service I
was thinking you know maybe I'll go into
the Foreign Service and maybe I'll you
know go to the hill I had this master's
degree and essentially in lobbying you
know and then this opportunity presented
itself
so when was that like was there an
ethical component that eventually struck
you where you started saying oh uh oh
yeah
totally see my my career was divided
into two halves the first half was in
analysis the directorate of intelligence
where you write you know the president's
Daily Brief you write for the
secretaries of state and defense for the
National Security advisor the CIA
director and so you're you're doing
you're you're offering up your analysis
to support policy
um I got bored with that about seven and
a half years into my my career and um as
it turned out I was the only person in
the CIA at the time that spoke both
Greek and Arabic fluently and so
um I applied for a position as a
counter-terrorism officer in Athens
uh working on Arab terrorist groups and
it sounds quaint now but Euro communism
and uh and I got the job so I went
through traditional operational training
and uh
and found that I had a knack for it so I
did two years in Athens I came back in
the summer of 2000 uh to head a group
that trained Middle Eastern intelligence
services and counter-terrorist
operations and then 911 hit and um I
found myself as the chief of
counter-terrorism operations in Pakistan
wow wow yeah so the Greek was a given
like you your grandparents were Greek
yes and when you you got a president all
you wanted was the gyro bladder the hero
seriously seriously man I love that
[Applause]
um
Greek Greece is beautiful Greece is
really spectacular oh my God in fact I
I'm jumping way ahead but when I got in
trouble uh the Greek Ambassador called
me and he said how can we be helpful and
I said you can give me Greek citizenship
and they did and not just they gave it
to me they gave it to all five of my
kids too way to go well Greece is mad at
the United States and the EU anyway so
they're like anything we can do John
yeah seriously
well and so and so it but you're you're
um your kind of idea about the CIA when
did it change when did you think you
know why yeah I I can tell you I can
tell you exactly when it changed
um I can tell you the the hour that it
changed okay on the night of uh March 28
2002 I led a series of raids that
resulted in the capture of Abu zubaida
who we believed at the time was the
number three in Al Qaeda
um those raids also netted many dozens
of I'm not allowed to say the number but
many dozens of al-Qaeda Fighters and
several Al-Qaeda mid-level leaders
um
there are a couple of things that
happened that night that changed my
perspective
one of them was we had captured so many
guys that night that we had to bring
them to our safe house for interrogation
in shifts right we could only fit like
10 at a time in the Paddy Wagon uh to
bring them to the safe house and
um
there were a bunch of guys working for
me
on loan from headquarters who I really
didn't like or respect
there was one in particular who was just
furious because he believed he should be
in charge
and in fact he had he had flunked out of
operational training so he he shouldn't
be in charge of a coffee clutch let
alone a counter-terrorism operation
so he brings the first load of prisoners
to the uh to the safe house
and they all have hoods on
like like sacks on their heads and I
said
why are they hooded
and he says we don't want him to see who
we are we don't want them to know our
identities and I said to him I got right
in his face and I said Are you seriously
telling me that you've never read the
Geneva Convention
Are you seriously telling me that you
don't know it's a [__] War crime to
hood people yeah and I said take those
hoods off
and he says I'm reporting you to
headquarters and I said no I'm reporting
you to headquarters for committing a war
crime
well we reported each other to
headquarters and headquarters took his
side oh [__]
because the Geneva Convention means
nothing
well we're at War they said I said
actually we're not at War there's been
no Congressional declaration of war
right yeah Al Qaeda is not a
not a uh
uh State actor no we have to treat them
as civilians and you can't Hood them
yeah
so that that was the first
inkling to me that the rules had changed
then I get back to headquarters and I'm
back let me think I'm back
like three weeks
I've just caught the purported number
three of Al Qaeda with these two hands
right
and I get passed over for promotion
um
so I go to the deputy director of the
counterterrorism center who was an old
friend of mine and I said what the heck
happened I said what do I need to do
catch Bin Laden how do I get promoted
around here
and he said that the promotion panel
determined that by turning them down
when they asked me if I wanted to go
through the torture training that I had
displayed a shocking lack of commitment
to counter-terrorism
they asked 14 people to be trained in
the use of these enhanced interrogation
techniques I was the only one who said
no and so they passed me over for
promotion well I ended up getting a much
better job I became the executive
assistant to the cia's deputy director
who was secretly anti-torture although
he never said so out loud did you win so
when you got when you did that and you
said hey uh they're like hey you guys
you should learn this and you said I'm
not really into that did you think at
that point that they would be maybe
looking at you differently from now on
you didn't think about that no I didn't
and and friends of mine from the the
time from the period uh tell me that
they completely turned on me back then
and I had no idea I had no idea so I I
mentioned to the deputy director I said
I I can't believe I got passed over for
promotion and then he gave me what's
called a field promotion he just ordered
me promoted
so at least I and see that's one of the
reasons why I thought I was okay you
know they used to call me the human
rights guy
and a friend of mine told me afterwards
you know that that was not a compliment
they weren't complimenting you nope
so yeah it was 2002 that my view of them
changed and their view of me changed wow
yeah that's incredible that is so
incredible yeah the human rights guy
that's not a compliment no um not a
problem and then that's what brings me
to my next question because the CIA is
inherently always involved in dark Shady
business and they are always in the
business of lying and hiding and doing
all this stuff so at no point like even
in this conversation John I don't trust
you
but but seriously like when you get
involved with an organization like that
you never know who your friends are and
and your allies yes it seems tricky and
I I don't know if I could handle that in
life but they have done everything from
uh using LSD on unsuspecting citizens
backing nearly 50 60 70 80 100 coups in
South America and all over the world
with this great reading if anybody out
there doesn't know
um and as we know now
torturing suspected terrorists or you
know or anybody that fits that bill
right so what in your opinion are some
of the most egregious and and horrible
things the CIA or the government has
been guilty of through
all right wow wow where do you even
begin you know you have to start really
with uh well if you're looking at
if you're looking at egregious things
against human beings you have to begin
with the LSD uh trials
um they dose people with LSD
not giving them any any warning that
they were doing this you know we we had
a CIA contractor there have been TV
shows and films made about them we had a
CIA contractor who was dosed with LSD
who had no idea what was happening and
he jumped out of a hotel window and
killed himself yeah um there are reports
which I've always assumed are true uh
that uh the CIA put LSD in
in
dough to make bread in a French Village
in the 1950s that made half the village
go completely crazy
the CIA worked hand in glove with Nazi
scientists through the 1950s and the
1960s
the CIA has overthrown countless
governments and in some cases like Iran
for example we're still paying the price
for that decision
uh the CIA has
instituted a torture program a an
international rendition program a secret
prison program uh they've spied on the
United States Senate and its
investigators I mean you could go on and
on volumes of books have been written
about this kind of thing so yeah it's
it's not a proud history yeah and right
now I'm finding it really difficult to
find any information on Kirchner and
Argentina and what's going on there
because I've been trying to share videos
of this alleged assassination but what I
do know is that any socialist government
that comes to power in South America
that it's a big [__] deal for America
and they go down there and the CIA most
likely I don't know tries to subvert
that democracy or do whatever and in the
I'll just interject here and say the in
the case of Eva Morales they kid they
got this woman that happened to be in a
picture with him and apparently said
that that was his underage lover and all
this stuff and then he raped her well
the police actually kidnapped this woman
and held her for multiple days without
food and forced her to make this
statement saying that the president of
Bolivia
raped me or whatever and she escaped
made it to somewhere else with her
family intact and was able to say hey
that stuff I just said I just made it up
the the police [__] made me say it so
this is something to be aware of in
America anybody from America listening
this is this is crazy what do you think
about that John side note well you know
pre-911 I would have my head would have
just bobbed up and down and I would have
said yeah the CIA does that kind of
things post 911
um there's a lot less of that uh and
it's because the CIA has so many more
important things to worry about
terrorism Iran North Korea Russia and
China those are what are called tier
zero issues meaning drop everything and
focus on this I remember I remember
hearing a senior officer give advice to
a junior officer who spoke Spanish and
was interested in making a career in
Latin America and the senior officer
said go make a career in Latin America
you'll never get promoted again and
you'll never find yourself in a position
of influence at headquarters because
nobody gives a [__] about Latin America
anymore and I found that to be true
because 9 11. wow why is that is there
are the resources not important enough
or do we have a good enough grip on it
or
well they're just I mean resources
believe it or not are finite especially
human resources and um you've got to
focus on the stuff that's the most
immediate and and you know people don't
realize that it's the White House that
sets the the cia's agenda
um if the White House believes that the
biggest problems the country faces are
Russia and China then everybody's going
to be working on Russia and China it's
not an accident for example that
that John Brennan created uh the Iran uh
it's called the Iran Mission uh at the
CIA to coordinate all Iran activities
government-wide we already had an Iraq
Mission we have a counter
um uh what's it called counter
proliferation Center a counter-terrorism
center it's it's those big tier zero
issues that everybody's focused on and
you know if you're inside the CIA too
you want to get promoted and you're not
going to get promoted working on
Paraguay yeah you're going to get
promoted working on Iran gotcha got
Korea well that would that would tell me
that South America is no longer a threat
and anything that's it's we have
absolute control you know Kissinger
actually said and this I think this is
true in the case of things like Maduro
because Maduro uh is socialist and a lot
of been populist in the way where they
voted for him and they like him uh but
all of a sudden there's food shortages
well Kissinger famously said who is this
great douchebag the worst the worst he
said you control the food you control
the people you control the uh means of
production as far as tractors and
whatever seeds and food distribution and
especially with uh what we call
conventional uh processed foods and
stuff like that
um and then all of a sudden the shelves
are empty in Venezuela and the media is
desperately trying to blame it on him
and so there's two sides to every story
always sometimes three yeah I'm finding
that human rights is is a word that the
United States uses as a club to beat
over countries over the head with to say
he's a dictator we're gonna get him yeah
but then the Saudis execute they behead
81 people in in one day and we don't
even make an official statement
yeah yeah yeah this is the great
wonderful world of hypocrisy that you
get to learn as you get older and you
read enough you know that hey this is
all American imperialism is a real bad
thing and we might be we might be the
Nazis this time yeah we're looking for
bad guys
um
so now you've you've written so many
books so many great and and I really
have to say thank you your time in the
CIA in your whole life I think you as a
Storyteller and a writer you're just
unbelievably talented oh thank you you
know I I'll tell you a kind of a funny
story about that my first book I I wrote
the first 60 pages and I gave it to my
wife and I said give it a read and tell
me what you think and um she reads it
and she comes back and she says I I hate
it
I said really she said it's terrible it
reads like a like a government report
and uh then she said listen I've I've
heard you tell these stories a thousand
times just write them the way you tell
them and it was that advice yeah that
made me just completely change my
writing style and so now that's that's
how I try to write I try to write it as
though I'm sitting you know across the
table from you and I'm telling you a
story
yeah and it's and it's your attention to
detail and the flow and the excitement
in your voice which you you know your
facts thank you fantastic man really I
appreciate it what's great is and I
would say it myself because I you may
not know much about me but I've I used
to hitchhike and hop trains and live the
homeless Bohemian lifestyle Across
America for about 10 years awesome and
that also in itself it gave me exciting
experiences to tell a story by through
you know what I learned and the wisdom
behind that and you have the same thing
ah thank you yeah and that brings me to
my next question because
um you wrote a book called doing time
like a spy how the CIA taught me to
survive and thrive in prison okay
cool cool title and uh
I wanted to ask you what does an average
day for an incarcerated whistleblower
stuck in prison what are some of the
best and worst things about your prison
stack
the worst things are are twofold one is
the monotony it really is Groundhog Day
every single day is just like every
other day you don't even know what day
it is from one to the next
um the other one is the the other bad
part is the guards
um
Dr Peter moskos of the John Jay College
um School of um
criminal justice said that the Bureau of
Prisons is little more than an
employment agency for otherwise
unemployable uneducated white men
uh and I found that to be exactly true
that there's a reason why our prisons
are all out in the Boondocks because
there's no other industry out there and
you know
people who flunk out of the local police
academy or get thrown out of the
military have to work somewhere and they
can't all deliver pizzas so they become
prison guards and I'm not saying that to
be mean that's I mean most of them
actually were pizza delivery guys before
they became prison guards
um and because they've got authority
over people uh they they can be cruel
like irrationally cruel
um so that was the other bad part
the normal day to tell you the truth and
this is what you need to do
as soon as you get into prison is come
up with a routine if you can come up
with a routine
um and regiment your day you're going to
be fine
so uh
you know everybody's got to work right
it's it's like slavery you have to work
and I made I think I made like
16 cents an hour something like that 14
cents an hour I don't even remember
anymore
and um
and I would get vast amounts of mail I
would get 60 70 80 letters a day from
people
and I decided on my very first day that
if somebody was going to take time out
of their day to write me an
old-fashioned letter I was going to
write back
and I ended up responding to more than
seven thousand letters uh while I was
there nice job John I answered every
single one of them so that would be a
good part of my day and then I would um
I would otherwise uh write I actually
wrote an op-ed for the Los Angeles Times
while I was incarcerated I wrote an
op-ed for the um the guardian I wrote an
article for the Los Angeles Review of
Books
so I was getting published by like major
Outlets while I was in prison and I was
writing them longhand on a legal pad and
uh and send them to these newspapers and
they would publish them
so I realized I had an audience and
um I had access to the media Jake Tapper
came up to prison to interview me
um I gave an interview from prison to
NPR
uh the Greek media wow they used to come
all the time I was in the Greek papers
all the time
and so I realized I had you know I had
an audience out there that was
interested in what I had to say so I
started writing this book and you know
it's it's kind of a serious book and
it's kind of a comedic book
um I talk about the 20 life lessons that
I learned at the CIA that I used in
prison to keep myself safe and at the
top of the social Heap and um and it
worked out I ended up winning as crazy
as it sounds I won two literary awards
for that book I won the Penn First
Amendment award which is huge it's one
of the big four with the Pulitzer the
Penn Faulkner and the Edgar Allan Poe
and I won the forward reviews Memoir of
the year for 2016. just crazy
but it worked out nicely
I mean
you're you're not you're Natural Born
that's the thing and then the story is
good and and the book is good I really
recommend anybody out there who likes to
read go get it thank you go get this
book it's good it's really doing time
like a spy it's called yeah how the CIA
taught me to survive and thrive in
prison and this is just one of many
books this guy has written and they're
all that exciting seriously
um so when you you got out of prison you
began working on this book
um what obligations did you have as far
as secrecy and stuff like that to the
CIA and the parole board what what could
you say yeah it was tricky right good
question
um well there there is no federal parole
board they uh they disbanded it in 1986
um because there's no federal parole
anymore but for the rest of my life I I
have to send everything I write to the
cia's Publications review board
and um
they didn't object
to that book but they've objected to
much of the other stuff that I've
written and I've had to go to the mat
with them a couple of times
um and uh one of the most recent books
that I wrote
um is is called um
uh the CIA Insider's Guide to
surveillance and surveillance detection
right right and they they blacked out
like an entire page
and so I appealed and they said you
can't say this stuff it's uh it's
classified properly and currently
classified as the terminology and I said
you know I got this stuff off of your
website
seriously
rather than approving it for publication
they
fake site
so now as the book is published
page near the end of the book that's
just completely blacked out so there's a
thing on the internet everybody it's
called the way back machine and you can
visit stamped points of time in the
internet also go to the CIA go see what
was being said about what 510 let's go
five years back and see what you can
find yeah exactly
but you know another another thing is I
decided that if the CIA is gonna gonna
you know beat on me for the last 15
years and try to ruin my life I'm gonna
try to make some money off of it yeah I
do and so I wrote
um the the uh what was my first book
called it was uh
my secret life in the cia's war on
terror the the reluctance by my secret
life of this in the cia's war on terror
yeah then I did doing time like a spy
how the CIA taught me to survive in
threat in prison then I did the
convenient terrorist Abu zabeta in the
weird Wonderland of American Secret Wars
then I did the CIA Insider's Guide to
the Iran crisis the CIA Insider's Guide
to disappearing and living off the grid
I like the CIA Insider's Guide to lying
and lie detection and the CIA Insider's
Guide to surveillance and surveillance
detection yeah yeah so how much how many
redactions overall and are they friendly
to you when you go and visit them or are
do they give you the eye
uh they pretend to be friendly like
we've never exchanged harsh words but
then they testified against me in the
grand jury yeah that's like police or
FBI or anybody else they're not your
friends but they really pretend like
they are oh they pretend like you are
listen something happened to me a few a
few years ago that that you know that I
want to tell you about because I think
every American should be aware that this
is how um how our government agencies
act I I was out of prison for uh
two years
and one night around seven o'clock my
doorbell rang and my youngest son who
was little little at the time he was I
guess four
he ran to the door before I could get up
and he answered it and I heard this
sugary sweet voice say hi is your daddy
home
and I thought oh you bastards
so I go up to the door and I'm it's not
my nature to be rude or hostile but I
was hostile and I said may I help you
and this guy says
hi Mr kiriaku uh I'm I'm special agent
uh Smith from the FBI and this is my
colleague special agent Jones
I said you guys have balls coming here
you know I'm represented by Council
and he says oh uh no no Mr kiriaku we're
not here about your case uh we're here
on another matter we were hoping you
could help us out with
and I said what
and he says well we know that when you
were at at Loretto you were friends with
Peter the Rabbit Calabrese
I said so
well
um you know Pete got out he went home I
said good for Pete
well Mr kiriaku we have reason to
believe that Pete has taken over
leadership of the banana crime family
and I said and you want me to rat out of
five families boss
I said get off my property and I slammed
the door and I called my lawyer
and then he called me back about 20
minutes later and he said they're not
going to bother you again
and they haven't they basically just
said we want to get you [__] murdered
how do you how does it sound well and
they did something else to me you know
it's funny
just a day or two before I left for
prison my lawyer pulled me aside and he
said listen I need to give you some
advice and you need to follow it
he said
doj is very upset that your sentence is
as short as it is very upset and they're
going to try to set you up inside
so he said don't make any friends
right and don't do anything that brings
attention to yourself
so I said okay I didn't really know what
he was talking about but I said okay
so I'm there let me think
I'm there about
eight or nine weeks
and
a guy that lives in my housing unit
he nice guy born in Afghanistan but but
moved here as an infant so
um you know he spoke like a like an
American he was a pharmacist who had an
oxy problem so he found himself
incarcerated yeah
so he comes up to me and he says hey
John there's a new guy here and he wants
to meet you he used to be the spokesman
for the Taliban
and I said not interested
not interested and he said oh okay I'll
tell him
so I heard from a couple of other people
that this guy wanted to meet me and I
told everybody I have no interest in
meeting this guy I don't want to speak
to him
so one day I'm out on the on the yard
walking around the track
and this like obviously Afghan looking
guy with a beard halfway down to his
waist starts walking towards me with his
hand out like to shake my hand
just as he puts his hand out I happen to
look past him and I see a guy in the
woods on the outside of the fence with a
camera with a long range lens
and it's pointed at me
so I put my hands up
and I said to the guy don't [__]
touch me
and he's got his hand out for me to
shake and I said don't [__] touch me
and he said oh come on man don't be like
that and I said get the [__] out of here
I don't have anything to say to you and
he says you and I have a lot in common I
said you and I have nothing in common I
used to try to kill people like you
and then I walked away
so later on I did a Freedom of
Information Act request on myself
because they're so stupid at the Bureau
of Prisons like I say it's just a
collection of rejects from society that
work there
um and sure enough they were trying to
set me up and that was just one of many
not many but several things that they
did to get because they wanted to add
time onto my sentence so they were
trying to get you on film shaking hands
with somebody from the Taliban to show
that you were somehow oh look at him
he's terrorist yeah I'm a traitor right
uh and the Taliban is this is an
extremist religious nut bar group from
the Middle East yeah
absolutely uh how many uh I I want to
stick to the questions I got but I have
so many personal questions I want to ask
you well I have you back you know
um sure
we got 15 minutes before it's uh your
time so
um so we're going through a lot of
turbulent times in human history with
the war yeah climate change dying
democracy at the hand of corporate
interest with you know the various
tactics they're using to confuse us all
and right and a worldwide rise in
fascism as we speak uh and then on to on
top of it all a nice creamy Global
pandemic so
how did we get here in your opinion and
where do you think we're going John
cariako
I think that well from from a CIA
perspective
um I I am not hopeful in any way
I think that the most important
um
issues that the American people face
are being ignored by government and I
mean especially climate change in in
1993 when Al Gore became vice president
he ordered that the CIA create something
called
um a National Environmental Center to
address climate change as an
intelligence problem and as soon as
George W Bush was elected uh he
disbanded that Center and it's never
reappeared at the CIA but can you
imagine the the things like population
transfers or food instability
that are on the horizon because of
climate change these are all very
important
intelligence uh challenges and they're
being ignored yeah um I I have to agree
with you too about how you know we we
claim to be this shining Beacon's hope
for democracy and human rights and civil
rights and civil liberties and it's just
simply not true it's just not true plain
and simple you can't be a Beacon of Hope
for human rights when you have secret
prisons and torture chambers and illegal
Renditions it's just not possible yeah
it's it's hypocritical yeah all the way
back to the banana republics all the way
back to the banana republics which which
we you know financed and armed and
supported and and carried on so yeah I
I'm not optimistic about about our
future I'm really not and I have to say
what I and especially I've just been
because I'm in Germany right now and
I've been reading off what's going on in
the UK and uh they passed a law in 2022
I had no idea that it's limited what
people could say in the streets as far
as protests they're giving more money to
police cracking down and then saying
we're going to frack and we're gonna
drill every piece of oil out of the UK
and uh
yes it's a little frightening it sure is
and the extinction Rebellion which is
this great group who is trying their
best to raise yes about climate change
um which is appeals to every rational
intelligent human being that the idea of
biodiversity makes sense it's important
yeah
um there were they were called a
terrorist group and they had to go to
court in order to get that that type of
attractive
I I I spoke at their um their big event
in uh I think it was in November
December last year in Berlin they're a
terrific group there's nothing terrorist
about them quite nice young people
ridiculous yeah so okay well it's good
to know that I'm not alone in my kind of
apathetic like here I am drinking as
much wine as I can in life living my
best life now John kiriaku approves good
um so I got one more question for you
um actually that was the uh that was the
last question
so I'll I'll just ask you
um what are some of the main topics that
are on your mind at this moment what are
you covering on your radio show and uh
how can we help your your cause oh thank
you thank you very much
um
well I'm on Facebook John kiriaku
k-i-r-i-a-k-o-u I'm on Twitter at John
kiriaku
um my radio show is called political
Misfits it's at
um sputniknews.com you go to the bottom
of the page and the link is there or
we're on Rumble it's it's both audio and
video on Rumble
um you know I'm concerned about probably
the same things that you're concerned
about I I'm deeply concerned about about
human rights and Democratic processes
which I believe are are under great
threat and it doesn't matter who's in
the White House the Democrats are no
better than the Republicans you know
it's funny to me I I challenged my best
friend from high school the other day he
and I talk all the time and he's a total
Trump Republican
and he he said something about
um the Democrats radical agenda and I
said Gary I gotta ask you what's radical
about it
and he just looked at me and I said
seriously though what's what's radical
you keep calling it The Radical agenda
and and that's a pretty strong word what
is it that's radical
and then he says well you know like the
whole
Green New Deal thing
and I said that that doesn't even make
any sense but what is it that's radical
about the green New Deal and he goes I
don't [__] know and I said you watch
Fox News too much
there's no difference between the
Democrats and the Republicans except on
the fringes they're both right of Center
parties one's just farther right than
the other both around both are corporate
both both are corporate I said man with
all due respect I said you wouldn't know
a radical if you walked up and
introduced himself yeah
you were up on Tucker Carlson and you
were just like this is my position I
don't necessarily agree with you but I'm
just here to try to like talk about if
somebody was yes yes and you know what
I've struck up a friendship with Tucker
he and I disagree on 99 of all issues
sure but he is a lovely guy he gave me
his he gave me his cell phone number
after my second or third time on the
show we went out for beers he's a lovely
guy he's nutty on some issues sure he's
nutty on a lot of issues
but you know when it comes to
whistleblowing and transparency he's up
there with the best of them I love it
because sometimes this political
Spectrum you get right and left and then
you start coming around to libertarian
and right anti-firing and then you you
meet somewhere that's right that's the
whole spectrum is is not a straight line
it's a circle and it meets at some point
I'm glad I'm not the only one that sees
it yeah
well we're going to let you go I mean
we're going to have you back I'm going
to bother you now I got your email you
got a friend for life hero I always
subscribing what you do so let's wave
goodbye to all these folks out in TV
Land bye everybody thanks for having
John kiriako on the show